healing-crystals-for-you.com 2019-07-03

# Privacy Policy For Healing Crystals For You

### Your privacy is as important to me as it is to you.   
Here's how I deal with it.  

My name is Liz Oakes and I’m the owner and founder of this website, “Healing-Crystals-For-You.com”. 

My own privacy is important to me when I visit other people's websites, so I understand how important privacy is. The information you share with me is as important to me as it is to you. 

I’ve taken steps under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) to make sure any information you give me is secure, only seen by people who need to see it, and within your control. 

You can find out exactly why I need the information, what happens to it, who will see it and how I keep it secure by reading this privacy policy. If you’re still unsure, you’ll be able to contact me.

I maintain the highest standards of honesty and fairness in everything I write for this website, and I apply exactly the same standards when I deal with the information you trust me with.

## Why I Need To Collect Information In The First Place

Some of the reasons I need to collect information are to:  

  *     run this site so it displays information correctly, and to improve it when it doesn't  

  *     make your experience of using the site more personal and enjoyable  

  *     improve the products and service I offer you  

  *     improve my customer service, and help me respond to your requests more efficiently  

  *     reply to any enquiries, questions or requests  

  *      send information which you agree to receive about topics I think will interest you.

## Why I Collect Your Personal Information  

I never collect personally identifiable information (that is, information which may identify you such as your name or email address) without your knowledge. 

If I ask for personal information it's because you have volunteered to give it to me, for example if you get in touch through my ‘contact’ page.

I only collect your personal information when I need it. I need it for these reasons:  

  *  When you contact me for any reason, using one of my contact forms, you agree to give me your name and email address so I can reply to you.  

  * If you fill in a form on the “[Your Crystal Story](https://www.healing-crystals-for-you.com/crystal-story.html)” pages where you write a story or ask a question about crystals, I ask for your name and email address. You can also send photographs. You don’t have to fill that information in or send photos if you don’t want to. If you do, the information and photo will appear on the page about your crystal story.  

  * This information remains on the website for as long as you want your story to stay. If you’d prefer it to be taken off, you just need to get in touch with me.  

  *  If you give me personal information, I give you a 100% promise in return that the information will be used only for the reason you’ve shared it.  

  * I hate spam. I will never send you any information you have not requested.   

## Where Your Information Goes  

I will never share your personal information with anyone for commercial or any other use. It will be used only for the purpose you provided it on this website. 

Sometimes, though, for specific reasons, I need to share your information with someone else. 

I make sure I only use other individuals and companies I know and trust. I have also been careful to make sure they are also compliant with the General Data Protection Regulation, so I am confident they will also keep your data safe.

The only company who may currently hold your information is:

  * If you submit your story to one of the “[Your Crystal Stories](https://www.healing-crystals-for-you.com/crystal-stories.html)” pages, SiteSell, the company which hosts my website, stores your information securely on their servers.

## Your Rights Within The General Data Protection Regulation  

Europe's General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) was introduced specifically to protect the data of individuals. Although at present it only protects people in Europe, my view is that its extremely high standards should be a protection for everyone, worldwide.

I value everyone who visits this website, wherever you may come from. Which is why all my policies and practices, not just those which impact on Europeans, follow GDPR's requirements. So this privacy policy is my statement to you of my commitment to protect your personal information. 

If you would like to update that information or you want to have it deleted from my records, you just need to [click on this link](https://www.healing-crystals-for-you.com/contact.html) and let me know. 

If you think your personal information is not being used properly and you want to make a complaint, you should firstly contact me and ask me to put right whatever is wrong, explaining the problem as clearly as you can.

If you’re not satisfied with my response, you have every right to lodge a formal complaint. The best way to do this is to contact a lawyer and say you want to complain under the terms of the GDPR.  

## How You Can Correct or Remove Your Personal Information

I provide this privacy policy as a statement to you of my commitment to protect your personal information. 

If you have submitted personal information through my website and would like that information deleted from my records or would like to update or correct that information, or if you have any further questions, please be sure to use [my contact page](https://www.healing-crystals-for-you.com/contact.html) to talk to me.  

## Non-personal Information And "Cookies"

Personal information, such as your name and email address, is never collected automatically. I only have it when you choose to give it me. 

However, when you visit Healing Crystals For You.com, some statistical information is collected automatically. The reason I collect it is so that I can constantly improve your experience of visiting my site. 

This type of information includes the name of your Internet Service Provider, your Internet Protocol address, the name of your internet browser, and other numerical data such as which pages you visited, how many pages you looked at and how long you stayed on the site. 

This information helps me know which parts of my site you’re most interested in. That means I can make sure I write articles which focus on the subjects you’re most likely to want to read.  

**Cookies** : 

That information is collected by means of “cookies”. A cookie is a tiny bit of code placed by this website on your computer. 

Each time you come here, your browser gives my computer that code so I know that you've come back. That helps me know the kinds of articles that are most helpful to you. 

## Cookies

**Statcounter:**

Statcounter is an online service which helps us to understand our visitors; for example, how visitors find our website, how long they spend on our site, which web pages they are most interested in etc.

 **I use Statcounter because better understanding how visitors are interacting with my website helps me to improve the content, design and functionality of my site. This allows me to offer a better online experience to my visitors.**

 **Statcounter uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on visitors and visitor activity on our website.** This data includes:

  * Time and date of visit (this can help us to identify and plan for busy periods on our website)   

  * IP address (this is a numerical label assigned to a device by an Internet Service Provider to enable the device to access the internet)
  * Browser and Operating System (this can help us to make sure that our website functions correctly in the browsers/operating systems used to access our site)
  * Device Information e.g. device type and screen size (this can help us to make sure that our website functions correctly in the devices used to access our site)
  * Referring Data e.g. a search engine link (this can help us to understand which search engines are helping visitors to find our website)  

Furthermore, when you visit my website a Statcounter cookie (called "is_unique") may be placed in your browser. This cookie is used only to determine whether you are a first-time or returning visitor and to estimate unique visits to the site.

You can learn more about cookies from StatCounter and set your browser to refuse same by [**clicking here**](http://statcounter.com/about/set-refusal-cookie/). For further details, please see the [Statcounter privacy policy](https://statcounter.com/about/legal/#privacy).

**Google Analytics Cookies:**

**I use a service called Google Analytics to analyse how you use this website. It collects demographic data and information about your interests, for example, by means of cookies.**

 **The cookies are kept on your computer, the information is shared with Google, which stores the information on its servers and then gives me statistical reports.**

 **Google's own privacy policy is[available here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads).**

Healing Crystals For You uses the information from Google Analytics to track the number of visits to the site and operating systems. 

**No personally identifiable information is obtained from these cookies.**

If you would rather your data is not collected via Google analytics, you can install its opt-out browser extension by **[clicking here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/)**.

If you want to, you can turn cookies off by disabling them in your browser. You can learn how to do this at [The About Cookies website](http://aboutcookies.org/). 

You can set your browser to accept or reject all cookies automatically, or they can notify you when a cookie is being requested so you can decide what to do.

 **Web beacons are similar**. They track your journey around a website, or a collection of websites. They’re most often used to monitor traffic to a site.

Disabling either cookies or web beacons should not cause a problem with the continued use of this website, but it may prevent some of its interactive features from working properly. 

## Advertising

I use third-party advertising companies to serve ads on this website. These companies use cookies and web beacons in their ads to check how many times you've seen an advertisement.

I do not provide them with any personally identifiable information for cookie or web beacon use, so they cannot personally identify you with that information from this website. You can opt out of personalized ads from up to 125 different ad networks by clicking on [this link](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/).  

## Mediavine Display Ads  

This website uses Mediavine to manage all third-party advertising on the website. Mediavine serves content and advertisements when you visit the website, which may use cookies. 

Mediavine may collect IP addresses and location to serve personalized ads. 

If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices to opt-in or opt-out of this data collection, please visit [networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1)

## Links To Other Websites

Healing Crystals For You.com contains  **links to other websites**  that may be of interest to you. However, once you have used them to leave our site, we do not have any control over that other website.

Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information you provide while visiting such sites.

These sites are not governed by this privacy statement. Always exercise caution by reviewing the privacy statement of the website in question before continuing to use it.

## Affiliate Products and Services

I recommend some products I love and I think you might, too, from affiliate companies on this website. You can find my separate policy about affiliates, including who they are and where you can find out how they use data, at [**this link**](https://www.healing-crystals-for-you.com/affiliate-disclosure.html).  

I receive an affiliate commission for some of the products or services sold on healing-crystals-for-you.com.  By clicking on a product or service link, you consent to that platform's use of cookies, as outlined in the link below. 

The affiliate services platforms we use are:

Amazon.com and  Amazon.co.uk - [Amazon Privacy Policy](https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=508088)

Exquisite Crystals.com - [Exquisite Crystals.com Privacy Policy](https://www.exquisitecrystals.com/privacy-policy-cookie-restriction-mode)

ShareASale - [ShareASale Privacy Policy  
](https://account.shareasale.com/PrivacyPolicy.pdf)

ClickBank - [ClickBank Privacy Policy](https://support.clickbank.com/hc/en-us/articles/115015510108-Privacy-Policies)  

Ka Gold Jewelry.com - [Ka Gold Jewelry.com Privacy Policy](https://www.ka-gold-jewelry.com/privacy-security.php)

EBAY - [EBAY Privacy Policy](https://www.ebayinc.com/our-company/privacy-center/)

## Social Media

You’ll notice on this website there are links to Facebook, Pinterest and YouTube. 

When you click on them or leave a comment, your browser connects directly with that site and sends information such as your IP address, the date and time of your visit and information about how you use the social site. 

Should you wish to prevent those platforms from collecting data, please view their individual policies by using the following links:   

  * [Google+ and YouTube  
](https://policies.google.com/privacy)

## Privacy And Children

I operate in compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act and Article 8 of the GDPR. This website is directed to adults. It is not directed to children under the age of 16. 

I operate my site in compliance with current regulations. I work hard to make sure that Healing-Crystals-For-You.com is a family-friendly site. 

However, it is not intended for use by children without parental supervision, particularly children under sixteen years of age. I will never knowingly collect or use personal information from anyone under 16 years of age. 

Children under that age must have permission from a parent or legal guardian before asking questions, sharing stories or buying anything from this site.

If you're worried about your children's activities or their privacy on this site, please e-mail me through my [contact page](https://www.healing-crystals-for-you.com/contact.html).  

## Information Transfer

If I ever sell healing-crystals-for-you.com, information you have given me voluntarily may transfer to the new owner. 

Should that happen, you will receive notice through my website of the change and I will make reasonable efforts to ensure that the purchaser honors any opt-out requests you might make.  

## Data Storage

Personally and non-personally identifiable information collected by this site is stored on our host's servers. That host is SiteSell, and they are located at 1000, Sant-Jean Boulevard, Suite 702, Pointe-Claire, Quebec QC H9R 5P1, Canada. 

If you would like to review your information stored on the SiteSell servers, then [**please click on this link**](https://www.healing-crystals-for-you.com/gdpr-review.html). You'll also be able to edit, download or delete any of your information from the servers when you click on that link. 

If you have submitted personally identifiable information through this website, and you'd like to update it or have it deleted entirely from my records, [please click on this lin](https://www.healing-crystals-for-you.com/gdpr-request.html)[k](https://www.healing-crystals-for-you.com/gdpr-request.html).  

## Updates To This Policy

Healing-crystals-for-you.com reserves the right to make changes in this policy. If there is a material change in our cookie and privacy practices, we will indicate on our site that those practices have changed and provide a link to the updated privacy policy. 

We encourage you to periodically review this policy so that you will know what information we collect and how we use it.

## Agreeing To Terms

If you do not agree to healing-crystals-for-you.com's privacy policy as posted here on this website, please do not consent to the setting of cookies and the collection and storage of your personally identifiable information.

Your explicit consent indicates acceptance of this privacy policy in its entirety.

If you have any particular worries, questions or comments about this policy, please use my [contact page](https://www.healing-crystals-for-you.com/contact.html) to let me know.

 **Last updated: 27th May 2018**
